

Steffen W. R. Werner

Postdoctoral Associate at the Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University, USA

Personal Info —

* Birthday

September 6, 1992 in Stendal, Germany

✓ Address

251 Mercer Street New York, NY 10012, USA

@ E-mail

steffen.werner@nyu.edu

Website

https://ninsteve.github.io

Programming Skills ——

MATLAB

Expert

LaTeX

00000 **Expert**

Python

Advanced

intermediate

Languages -

German



English



Steffen W. R. Werner is an encouraged young researcher active in the fields of scientific machine learning and model order reduction, involving numerical linear algebra and scientific computing. During his scientific career, he published 10 journal articles, 2 book chapters, 9 conference papers, as well as 3 open-source software packages.

Professional Experience

since 09/2021 Postdoctoral associate. Courant Institute, New York University, USA. 10/2016-08/2021 Doctoral researcher, Max Planck Institute Magdeburg, Germany. 05/2016-09/2016. Student employee, Max Planck Institute Magdeburg, Germany. 10/2014-01/2016 • Development and maintenance of MATLAB toolboxes. 01/2016-04/2016 Industrial intern, proALPHA Business Solutions GmbH, Germany. Application programming. Analysis of modern version control systems. Student employee, 10/2013-09/2014 Otto von Guericke University Magdeburg, Germany.

• Tutor for mathematical/engineering courses.

Education

10/2016-08/2021 Doctoral studies in applied mathematics, Otto von Guericke University Magdeburg, Germany. • summa cum laude (excellent). 10/2014-09/2016 Master of Science in applied mathematics, Otto von Guericke University Magdeburg, Germany. • very good with distinction. Bachelor of Science in applied mathematics, 10/2011-09/2014 Otto von Guericke University Magdeburg, Germany. • very good with distinction.

Research Interests

scientific computing, scientific machine learning, model order reduction, data-driven modeling, numerical linear algebra, optimization and control, mathematical software

Awards

03/2020 **Best Paper Award Automatisierungstechnik** at - Automatisierungstechnik, De Gruyter, Austria. 06/2019 SIAM Student Chapter Certificate of Recognition

Society for Industrial and Applied Mathematics (SIAM), Philadelphia, USA.

Selected Publications

P. Benner and S. W. R. Werner. Frequency- and time-limited balanced trun-[1] cation for large-scale second-order systems. Linear Algebra Appl., 623:68-103, 2021. 10.1016/j.laa.2020.06.024 open access

J. Saak, D. Siebelts, and S. W. R. Werner. A comparison of second-order model order reduction methods for an artificial fishtail. at - Automatisierungstechnik, 67(8):648-667, 2019. doi 10.1515/auto-2019-0027

P. Benner, S. Gugercin, and S. W. R. Werner. Structure-preserving inter-[3] polation of bilinear control systems. Adv. Comput. Math., 47(3):43, 2021. do 10.1007/s10444-021-09863-w OPEN ACCESS

[4] P. Benner and S. W. R. Werner. MORLAB – Model Order Reduction LABoratory (version 5.0), 2019. see also: http://www.mpi-magdeburg.mpg.de/projects/